Nickel Boys is a drama, history film directed by RaMell Ross.
Chronicles the powerful friendship between two young Black teenagers
navigating the harrowing trials of reform school together in Florida.
Elwood, played by Ethan Herisse.
Turner, played by Brandon Wilson.
Hattie, played by Aunjanue Ellis-Taylor.
Spencer, played by Hamish Linklater.
Blakeley, played by Gralen Bryant Banks.
Harper, played by Fred Hechinger.
Nickel Boys is a 2024 American historical drama film based on the
2019 novel The Nickel Boys by Colson Whitehead.
It was directed by RaMell Ross, who wrote the screenplay with Joslyn Barnes.
Starring Ethan Herisse, Brandon Wilson, Hamish Linklater, Fred Hechinger, Daveed Diggs, Jimmie Fails, and Aunjanue Ellis-Taylor, the story
follows two African-American boys, Elwood (Herisse) and Turner (Wilson), who are sent to an abusive reform school in 1960s Florida.
The film is inspired by the Dozier School for Boys, a now-closed Florida
reform school notorious for its abusive treatment of students.
The film was shot from a first-person point-of-view, with
filming taking place in Louisiana in late 2022.
It premiered at the 51st Telluride Film Festival on August 30, 2024, and had a
limited theatrical release by Amazon MGM Studios on December 13, 2024.
It was named one of the top 10 films of 2024 by the American Film Institute and received numerous accolades, including the award for Best Cinematography at the 40th Independent Spirit
Awards, a Best Motion Picture – Drama nomination at the 82nd Golden Globe Awards and two nominations at the 97th Academy Awards for Best Picture and Best Adapted Screenplay.
IndieWire named it the best film of the 2020s, as of 2025, and it has
been cited by others as among the best of the 21st century.
The film explores themes of florida, new york city, sexual
abuse, based on novel or book, alligator.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.